[Music]
I just wanted to say thank you so much
for letting me have the extraordinary
experience of actually hosting the event
some times which was pretty amazingly
exciting for me to meet such incredible
human beings and actually have a
conversation where I wasn't completely
sunk for the lack of knowledge largely
because of the vigil itself and your
articles that you wrote which is how I
actually met you Susie is that I was
tweeting out her article on what was it
it was a way it's the the play on the
movie title we are all Julian what was
it totally it was a play on a film title
I remember and but what really was so
incredibly valuable is that I started
listening to the vigils and as someone
who is you know I'm not a journalist um
I'm certainly I care about the world was
an incredible education for me and in
fact I was going to suggest Joe Lauria
you know they there are newspapers of
record I think this vigil is a bloody
record of the most astonishing body of
activism of you know help me here John
you were nodding your head there but you
know just incredible wealth of valuable
human positions on how society should
run and what are the what are the
terrible structural disastrous
structural nightmares that we have to
deal with now which is basically I mean
I know we all have different political
viewpoints but I think what's undeniable
government is out of control on this
planet and if it isn't all governments
it certainly certain governments that
have such sway over all other
governments that we've got a real
like sci-fi movie in the making on this
planet we have the potential for us to
be truly the horror of George Orwell's
vision of a you know somebody with a
boot in the back of their neck forever
you know and so I was going to suggest
that this vigil is very carefully and
with great reverence given to the what
is it the American government upcycled
government the American Library of
Congress or whatever I mean this is like
um you know I don't know if all of you
have taken it what its historic it's my
it's the thing is is it's almost like a
time capsule of every bloody time that
human beings have faced tyranny this is
the discussion that would have been had
yes it's updated with you know the
technology that we're facing now is even
more daunting than it was but I said
this on several of the vigils you know
2,400 years ago Aristotle was describing
to a tee the very methods of tyranny and
their unchanging I mean I guess you
could say you know the wheel is a wheel
you know you can't improve on it you
figure out how to do tyranny you can't
really improve on it except we've got
this terrifying technological
improvement and if there was ever more
evidence that you needed that we live
under a tyranny on this planet and that
there's the discussions that have
occurred during this vigil over the last
15 months are really probably some of
the most important things that people
should listen to right now on the planet
because they consist of experts within
the field like Ray McGovern and John
Kiriakou and experts in whistleblowing
and journalists and I mean like you if
you want a crash course in what to be
thinking about and the problems that we
face just watch all these vigils they're
awesome and then as a another item that
I think is critical that anybody who's
watching this you have a
you see to find an example that you can
actually sync with to show your friends
how they're being lied to so that you
can get more and more people to address
the fact that they are so manipulated
both in school in universities in the
you know the rather frightening if any
of you have big Kindle users which I am
myself of the weird and strange things
where you suddenly find books missing
from your library and when you look them
up it says we no longer have the
publishing or whatever it is they have
so many subtle ways now of removing our
property even you know the property of
owning a book I have thousands of books
on Kindle and at first I thought this
was the greatest you know revolution in
the history of mankind to me were able
to walk around with a library in your
pocket but of course like all of these
technical logical advances they carry
with it and I have to believe that this
was understood when they started
creating all these things they carry
with it tremendous tremendous control
over what we have access to
I mean think of it would it be that
far-fetched to imagine that Amazon would
say you know we don't like Vivian
Kubrick we're actually going to get
we're gonna give her all her money back
but we're gonna take all her Kindle
books away which have all my notes in it
and all my you know highlights or I
found it with my iTunes or podcasts I
mean they can go in a second and unless
you're paying attention you don't
realize that they're even gone except
when you're starting to look for it so
you know everybody needs to if they if
they're cognizant of these things they
need to start talking to their friends
who are oblivious either through being
too busy or just oblivious because they
can't confront it it's so hard to
confront these things to actually like
acknowledge that we face such an you
know I don't want to give them a good
hard on thinking about the power they
have but they have such power
Oh gross and if we allow them also to
remove paper money and make everything
plastic it takes them one second to just
completely I mean we've all see what
defunding can do right Susie suffered
from it you know that we we have so many
issues that have come up on this vigil
and I'm trying to sort of put all
together the ones that I think a super
bloody important during the Third Reich
what did they do to the Jews they closed
down their businesses they wouldn't let
them conduct any kind of way of bringing
income into their lives so they became
very poor and starving in desperate
people they also wouldn't let them have
jobs you know they literally were
outlawed you were not allowed to have
Jewish teachers Jewish doctors whatever
you know if you think for one second
that Julian could get a job as a teacher
or get a job at anything after this even
if he gets out of this nightmarish
situation they're going to continue to
persecute him unless we all of us really
get on the case about how are the ways
that you can unperson somebody and these
days it's so invisible it's so hard for
people even tell that somebody's been
unperson
you know so there's a lot here there's a
lot I mean obviously the the the the the
the cause of saving Julian has not
finished and like Emmy is going to be
carrying on and but all of us
individually our job is not finished
here just like oh the visuals over right
okay
I'll go back into not going online and
you know mouthing off about everything I
mean I don't know if anyone looks at my
Twitter feed but if I don't soon get a
court order for stalking President Trump
I don't know who shouldn't get a court
order on them because I bloody tweeted
that now I'm delusional but I have this
idea at least somebody's looking at the
tweets that he gets back you know get it
you know and I send them to Rudy
Giuliani as well and I just think that
them you've got to keep doing something
and the most important thing is that
you've got to find real examples for
yourself that you
share with your friends of how people
are unperson
how they are defunded D platformed and
how that parallels what happened during
the Third Reich and you don't have to
read 400 books to understand what
happened in the 3rd right people lost
their form of employment they lost their
income they were they even lost their
passports for Christ's sake and hello
Julian didn't have his passport for a
long time in history I mean do you see
all the different ways that government
has become the equivalent of a despotic
bureaucracy and you know when people
going oh we need to stay near you it
means I can go and work in Paris if I
feel like it it's like Jesus Christ
people don't you see how the
centralization of power is exactly the
vision that George Orwell had for us so
you know not only am i trying to
encapsulate what I think is very
important for people to focus on but I
also want to show you that what Suzy did
one human being admittedly kick-ass you
know pistol of a woman but you know this
there's plenty more of Suzy's in the
world that you can do a lot on your own
and number one thing is to not shut up
about it
don't just think that you'd go out in
the street corner for an afternoon you
go save Julian you know you've actually
got to do it to the point where people
are going Oh God and that's what you
have to get to is is that place in
yourself you have to realize what's at
stake and you've got to be brave because
it takes bravery to face the danger
we're in it's that I'm sorry I'm I I am
the worst chatterbox so I just say two
things there one every time somebody
tells me that I'm brave I say no I'm
stubborn
I'm really really stubborn
I refuse to quit I refuse to give up
it's not about bravery it's about
determination and there's my two cents
and I'm sorry good
this is such an important conversation I
want to add something that Craig Murray
told me a couple of weeks ago he said
that when he first reported back to his
foreign minister that the CIA and the
Uzbek Intelligence Service were
torturing prisoners he sent this
notification back in a cable that he had
classified top secret
apparently the minister was livid that
he had put that he had put this in
writing and so they called him back to
London for consultations well it just so
happened that Craig's best friend from
the Foreign Service was the director of
human resources for the Foreign Service
the entire Foreign Service British
Foreign Service and so he invited Craig
to lunch and he said listen they're
talking about you in the hall and the
minister is very very upset that you put
this torture report in writing so I'm
prepared to offer you ambassador to
Denmark if you withdraw the report and
he said they had been friends for 30
years and he didn't know me at all and
he said what's the alternative he said
the alternative is you hire a criminal
defense attorney and he said then I quit
that is something that to me is a
natural normal thing to do I don't think
that I like to think that I don't know
anybody that would have taken ambassador
to Denmark rather than stand on his
principles it's you're right it's not
bravery it's stubbornness because in our
hearts we know that we've been doing the
right thing there's not a choice to be
made there's only one choice and the
choice is to do the right thing that's
it and then when we see it injustice
like we've seen with Julian we have to
stand up and we have to say that's an
injustice until we've convinced
everybody and we right the wrong
that's what this is all about look at my
strength we have in numbers once I mean
look how much stronger
we have been with unity for Jay with a
hundred of us working together and
speaking then if it was just one of us
on our soapbox and that's not to say
that you shouldn't start with one
because I tell you what every mass
movement starts with somebody somebody
who's prepared to go out and maybe make
a dick of themselves if needs be maybe
be a little bit embarrassed on the first
occasion but to actually attract others
to enter build a mass movement it does
start with one but the the 350 million
social media impressions came as the
result of our collective efforts and our
collective solidarity and none of us
could have achieved that by ourselves
but together we've been able to and and
I I just wanted to say something else is
that I was actually watching in real
time when Laura luma she had on Laura
luma hashtag on Twitter it was at 9.2
million and I watched it in real-time go
from 9.2 million to 274 people or 273 so
I watched it right I the reason why no
but I just want to say something the
reason why that's so important is that
people have to understand they know how
important it is when people see
something like 9 million people wow
this is important so don't be
discouraged if anything on social media
goes oh 71 people only looked at this
for over the last year they screw around
with those numbers I saw it in real time
before my eyes I tweeted it out I
tweeted out to president as per usual
but I just wanted to really underline
the fact safety in numbers right they're
trying to discourage you by thinking
that only you know your Aunt Mabel and
the cat is watching so don't let that
discourage you because they're they know
how that is discouraging understand that
this is huge I saw it with my own eyes
9.2 million hashtag Laura luma go down
to 273 people in front of my bloody face
so please please please the same thing
so when I say this three
hundred and fifty million I mean that
was a long time ago that we hit 350
million so it's actually much more than
that but that was our own analytic
tracking programs that we set up to be
able to track the hashtags we saw that
even though we could see twenty thousand
accounts tweeting to the hashtag I was
just painting in it Twitter when it
finally trended on Twitter and
Washington DC and in Sydney Australia
and said two hundred and seventy people
have tweeted about this and we're
sitting on this like 10 15 20 times that
amount you know so yeah absolutely
and and we've seen also in our YouTube
streams like people will come and go by
the hundreds but it'll be one static
amount watching it'll say like 180
watching live and it'll say it'll
maintain that number for like two hours
but we can see from the YouTube chat you
know that there's just absolutely not
the case so yeah you have to take the
numbers with a grain of salt but I
wanted to just speak to what you're
saying before about your Kindle and is
their ability to censor digital archives
because this is what Julian's been
harping on about for years and it's also
why WikiLeaks was established in the
first place was to create a permanent
indelible unsensible record of
information in the public interest so
and actually in the article I put out
last week friend Julian Assange part 1 I
quoted him talking about the ways that
mainstream media are retro actively
censoring their digital archives and he
said that when they delete historical
content from the archives it's not just
that their article no longer exists but
that the article never existed they are
literally deleting human history and
when I wrote that article I went back
and the reason it took me months to
produce it is because I went and read
every single tweet about WikiLeaks and
Julian Assange not just from them but
about them for the entire year of 2010
and 90% of those
were all broken gone vanished from the
internet the history of WikiLeaks the
public story the narrative conversations
the blog posts the media about them
vanished as if they never existed so
that's why WikiLeaks is so important and
it's why WikiLeaks is such a threat
because WikiLeaks was preserving an
accurate record of human and diplomatic
and governmental and corporate history
that those entities themselves don't
allow to exist
[Music]
you